icc-cricket.com 2019-04-03

# Privacy Policy - Legal | ICC Cricket

**1\. INTERNATIONAL CRICKET COUNCIL PRIVACY POLICY**

1.1 ICC Business Corporation FZ LLC is a Limited Liability Company incorporated under the regulations of the Dubai Creative Clusters Authority and has its registered address at Shared Desk 2-55, Second Floor, Building 2, Dubai Media City, United Arab Emirates. Our administrative office address is at Street 69, Dubai Sports City, Sheikh Mohammed Bin Zayed Road, PO Box 500070, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.

1.2 ICC Business Corporation FZ LLC operates in conjunction with various group companies, including International Cricket Council Limited, International Cricket Council FZ LLC, ICC Americas, IDI Mauritius Ltd and ICC Development (International) Limited. ICC Business Corporation FZ LLC and these group companies form the International Cricket Council Group.  

1.3 The International Cricket Council Group (collectively referred to as **"ICC"** , **"we"** , **"us"** ), take our data protection and privacy responsibilities seriously. This policy ( **"Privacy Policy"** ) describes how we collect, process, use, disclose and transfer your personal information as a data controller. It covers instances when you contact us, use our services or interact with our websites, such as [https://www.icc-cricket.com](https://www.icc-cricket.com/), and ICC mobile apps (together **"ICC Websites"** ).

1.4 The entity responsible for your personal information is ICC Business Corporation FZ LLC.

**2\. Terms of Use**

2.1 Use of the ICC Websites is subject to our [Terms of Use](https://www.icc-cricket.com/about/the-icc/legal-notices/website-terms-of-use).  

**3\. Updates**

3.1 We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to keep it up to date with legal requirements and the way we operate our business. Please regularly check this page for the latest version of this Privacy Policy. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will seek to inform you by notice on our website or email ( **"Notice of Change"** ).

3.2 Your continued use of the ICC Website following an amendment or Notice of Change indicates your acceptance of any changes.

**4\. Third Party Websites**

4.1 ICC Websites may link you to other websites. We are not responsible for the way in which third party websites operate or the way in which they may process any personal information, which you provide to them. It is important that you understand this and check their respective privacy policies and terms of use.

4.2 Microsites which allow for the purchase of merchandise and tickets for example which are accessible from the ICC Websites are operated by third parties which we have licensed to carry out such activity and subject to such third parties' terms and conditions and privacy policies. We are not responsible for the operation of such microsites.  Again, we strongly recommend that you review and understand their terms and conditions and privacy policies.

**5\. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHEN AND WHY WE USE IT**

In this section you can find out more about: 

  * the types of personal information we collect
  * when we collect personal information
  * how we use personal information 

**5.1 ICC Websites**

5.1.1 We will collect technical information about you, including the internet protocol ( **"IP"** ) address used to connect to the internet, browser type and version, time zone setting, operation system and platform, as well as information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators ( **"URL"** ), clickstream to, through and from our site, items you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visit to certain pages, page interaction information, and methods used to browse away from the page.

5.1.2 We may use your personal information to administer the ICC Websites and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes. 

5.1.3 We use cookies to improve the ICC Websites to ensure that the content is presented in the most effective manner for you. Similarly, we use cookies to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you. 

5.1.4 We use your personal information to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

**5.2 Surveys and Quizzes**

5.2.1 To engage in, and analyse the results of, surveys with you about to enable us to provide a more personal and bespoke service. Surveys may be conducted in a number ways, including by email, or other electronic means, as well as onsite at ICC events. 

**5.3 Matches, Events and Promotions**

5.3.1 We regularly arrange events and special promotions to introduce ICC to new customers and fans.  If you come to one of these events, or take part in a promotion, we may ask for your personal details to help us run the event or promotion and keep in touch with you about our services and any special offers that we think may be of interest subsequently.  Any information which you provide will be used in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and you can unsubscribe from further communications from us at any time. 

**5.4 Gamification**

5.4.1 We may collect personal information about you through your use of interactive games that utilise or license ICC intellectual property rights.  Some of these games may be operated by our licensed partners.  To learn more about this please visit the privacy policies of our partners.

**6\. LEGAL BASIS FOR USING YOUR DATA**

6.1 We will only collect, use and share your personal information where we have an appropriate legal basis to do so. Appropriate legal bases include:

6.1.1 where we need to use your personal information to perform a contract or take steps to enter into a contract with you;

6.1.2 our legitimate interests as a commercial organisation, for example; we may use customer contact information to keep our customers informed about changes and other important service messages; we may also let you know about special offers that may be of interest to you - in these cases we will respect your privacy rights and ensure you may object to processing as explained in section 12 below - "Your Rights";

6.1.3 where we need to use your personal information to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation that we have; and

6.1.4 where we have your consent to using your personal information for a particular activity, for example to share with you special offers from ourselves and our partners that we consider may be of interest to you.  

6.2 If you would like to find out more about the legal bases upon which we process personal information please contact us at [enquiry@icc-cricket.com].

**7\. HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WITH OTHERS**

7.1 We work closely with a number of trusted partners with whom we need to share information to help us provide our services:

7.1.1 our group or affiliate companies around the world, including International Cricket Council Limited, ICC Business Corporation FZ LLC, ICC Development (International) Limited, ICC Americas and IDI Mauritius Ltd;

7.1.2 selected third parties including:

7.1.2.1 our commercial partners, our members, business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you.  A list of our current commercial partners and members can be found [here](https://www.icc-cricket.com/about); 

7.1.2.2 service providers that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our service providers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users; and

7.1.2.3 analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site and services to you;

7.1.3 other third parties who help manage our business and deliver services.  For example, these may include IT service providers who help manage our IT and back office systems; and

7.1.4 with fraud and crime prevention agencies and providers, to comply with legal obligations.

7.2 From time to time we may share information about you with government organizations and agencies, and international organisations, to comply with applicable laws, regulations and rules, and legitimate requests from law enforcement, regulatory and other governmental or international agencies, or when to do so is in our legitimate interests, even if we are not compelled to share that information by applicable law.  

7.3 If, in the future, we sell or transfer some or all of our business or assets to a new group company or third party, we may disclose or transfer information relating to our business or assets to such entity.

**8\. MORE ABOUT DIRECT MARKETING, PROFILING AND AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING**

**8.1 Direct marketing**

8.1.1 We are committed to keeping you informed about our products and services or those of our commercial partners and members in line with your personal preferences. If we communicate with you about our products and services we will always provide you with an opportunity to stop receiving such marketing material. 

8.1.2 We will usually send this by email but we may choose to contact you in other ways for example by phone, post, SMS, social media channels and/or other electronic means if that is more appropriate. **You can ask us to stop sending you marketing material at any time by contacting us at** [enquiry@icc-cricket.com].

**8.2 Managing your marketing preferences**

8.2.1 To protect your privacy rights and to ensure you have control over how we manage marketing with you:

8.2.1.1 we will take steps to limit direct marketing to a reasonable and proportionate level and only send you communications which we believe may be of interest or relevance to you; 

8.2.1.2 You can also click the "unsubscribe" link that you will find on any online communications which you receive, or contacting us at [enquiry@icc-cricket.com].

8.2.1.3 you can change the way your browser or device manages cookies, which may be used to deliver online advertising, by following the settings on your browser as explained in section 11 below.

8.2.2 We recommend you routinely review the privacy policies and preference settings that are available to you on any social media platforms.

**8.3 More about profiling and analytics**

8.3.1 We may use some of the information you provide to us in order to perform profiling and analytics with the data.  We will do this either with your consent or where it is in our legitimate interests.  

8.3.2 One of the methods by which we do this is by installing and using Cookies on your browser or device.  You can learn more about how to adjust settings relating to Cookies on your browser and device, and about our Cookie Policy in the section titled Cookies and Mobile, below.

8.3.3 Some of the legitimate purposes for which we profile and analyse data include:

8.3.4 to allow us to enhance our provision of services to you;

8.3.5 to provide you with tailored content online and optimise your experience of the ICC Websites;

8.3.6 to offer  personalised products when you use ICC Websites, attend events, take part in promotions or use our services;

8.3.7 to obtain a better understanding of our customers, what you would like to see from us, and how we can improve our services for you;

8.3.8 to share advertising material we believe may be of interest to you, including from our commercial partners;

8.3.9 to help us operate our services more efficiently.

8.3.10 If you are a data subject with rights under the GDPR then we will take steps to ensure that prior to profiling your information for a legitimate interest that our legitimate interest is not overridden by your own interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.  If you are a data subject with rights under the GDPR you may have rights to object to us profiling your personal information.  You can learn more about profiling and analytics under the GDPR [here](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612053).

**9\. TRANSFERRING PERSONAL INFORMATION GLOBALLY**

9.1 We operate our business on a global basis. The countries to which we commonly disclose your personal information include the United Arab Emirates ( **"UAE"** ), the United States of America ( **"USA"** ), and the United Kingdom ( **"UK"** ). Some of these countries which are outside of the European Economic Area, for example, the UAE and the USA, have laws which do not offer, in the opinion of the European Commission or other supervisory authorities, an adequate level of data protection. 

We will always strive to adopt the highest standards of privacy protection, wherever your personal information is located and adopt appropriate measures (consistent with locally applicable laws) to secure an adequate level of privacy protection. We will take appropriate steps to ensure that transfers of personal information are in accordance with applicable laws and carefully managed to protect your privacy rights and interests. Transfers will be limited to countries which are recognized as providing an adequate level of legal protection or where we can be satisfied that alternative arrangements are in place to protect your privacy rights. 

9.2 You have a right to contact us at [enquiry@icc-cricket.com]. for more information about the safeguards we have put in place to ensure the adequate protection of your personal information when this is transferred as mentioned above. See also the section titled "Your Rights", below.

**10\. HOW WE PROTECT AND STORE YOUR INFORMATION   **

**10.1 How we protect your information**

10.1.1 We invest an appropriate level of resources to protect the security and confidentiality of personal information.

10.1.1.1 We offer the use of secure communication transmission software (known as "secure sockets layer" or "SSL") that encrypts all information you input to our website before it is sent to us. SSL is an industry standard encryption protocol and this ensures that the information is reasonably protected against unauthorised interception;

10.1.1.2 We also follow security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information which you have given us, to prevent unauthorised access to that information; 

10.1.1.3 We take all reasonable and appropriate steps to protect your personal information but cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose to us via email or online; and

10.1.1.4 Where you disclose information to us using one of our mobile apps, please ensure that your device remains safe. We cannot be held responsible for any data misuse arising from unauthorised access to your device.

**10.2 Storing your personal information**

10.2.1 We will store your personal information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes for which it was collected, as explained in this Privacy Policy. Where your information is no longer required, we will ensure it is disposed of in a safe manner. In some circumstances we may need to store your personal information for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, regulatory, tax, accounting requirements.  Should you require information about how we retain particular information you can contact us at [enquiry@icc-cricket.com].

10.2.2 In specific circumstances we may store your personal information for longer periods of time so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges, or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation relating to your personal information or dealings.

**11\. COOKIES AND MOBILE  **

**11.1 Our policy on "cookies"**

11.1.1 A cookie is an element of data that a website sends to your browser, which then stores it on your system. Cookies may collect personal information about you. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of the ICC Websites. Cookies also allow us to make the ICC Websites more user-friendly by, for example, allowing us to take you to the language site of last use, so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our website.

11.1.2 Cookies will be deployed on your device when you visit the ICC Websites unless you indicate that you do not wish this to happen or if you have turned this feature 'off' in your web browser or device settings.

11.1.3 For more information about how our cookies work and information about how to manage your cookie settings please visit our [Cookie Policy](https://www.icc-cricket.com/about/the-icc/legal-notices/cookie-accepting-policy). 

**12\. YOUR RIGHTS - LEGAL RIGHTS AVAILABLE TO HELP MANAGE YOUR PRIVACY**

12.1 **You may have certain legal rights regarding your personal information depending upon the country you are in or how we interact with you.   You can learn more about this in this section.**

12.2 Subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy we guarantee that you have following key rights wherever you are:

12.2.1 **To access your personal information.**   We will tell you what personal information we hold about you and can provide you with a copy of this;

12.2.2 **To seek rectification of that personal information.** Where the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate we will rectify this, upon your request.  Note that this right may be limited in terms of the scope of detail that we will or can rectify;

12.2.3 **To lodge a complaint to us.**   We will receive and handle your complaints in accordance with best practice and depending upon where you are and whether we are subject to it, any applicable law.  

12.3 **If you are resident in the European Union or otherwise benefit from rights as a data subject under the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), you will have certain additional rights in relation to our handling of your personal information.   **

12.3.1 To erase personal information;

12.3.2 To restrict the processing of your personal information;

12.3.3 To transfer your personal information;

12.3.4 To object to the processing of personal information;

12.3.5 To object to how we use your personal information for direct marketing purposes;

12.3.6 To obtain a copy of personal information safeguards used for transfers outside your jurisdiction; and

12.3.7 To lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority.

12.4 A further explanation of these general key rights and the GDPR specific rights is outlined in the sections below.  

12.5 You may have other rights depending upon the country you are in.   You may therefore have rights to lodge a complaint to a local privacy authority, however whether you lodge a complaint and who you lodge it with is solely your responsibility. 

12.6 If you wish to access any of these rights, we may ask you for additional information to confirm your identity and for security purposes, in particular before disclosing personal information to you. We reserve the right to refuse to provide this additional information if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive.

12.7 You can exercise your rights by contacting us at [enquiry@icc-cricket.com]. Subject to legal and other permissible considerations, we will make every reasonable effort to honour your request promptly or inform you if we require further information in order to fulfil your request.  

12.8 We may not always be able to address your request fully, for example if it would impact the duty of confidentiality we owe to others, or if we are legally entitled to deal with the request in a different way. 

**12.9 Right to access personal information  **

12.9.1 You have a right to request that we provide you with a copy of your personal information that we hold and you have the right to be informed of; (a) the source of your personal information; (b) the purposes, legal basis and methods of processing; (c) the data controller’s identity; and (d) the entities or categories of entities to whom your personal information may be transferred.

**12.10 Right to rectify or erase personal information  **

12.10.1 You have a right to request that we rectify inaccurate personal information. We may seek to verify the accuracy of the personal information before rectifying it. 

12.10.2 You can also request that we erase your personal information in limited circumstances where:

12.10.2.1 it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected; or

12.10.2.2 you have withdrawn your consent (where the data processing was based on consent); or

12.10.2.3 following a successful exercise of the right to object (see right to object in section 12.13 below); or

12.10.2.4 it has been processed unlawfully; or

12.10.2.5 to comply with a legal obligation to which ICC is subject. 

12.10.3 We are not required to comply with your request to erase personal information if the processing of your personal information is necessary: 

12.10.3.1 for compliance with a legal obligation; or

12.10.3.2 for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

**12.11 Right to restrict the processing of your personal information  **

12.11.1 You can ask us to restrict your personal information, but only where:

12.11.1.1 its accuracy is contested, to allow us to verify its accuracy; or

12.11.1.2 the processing is unlawful, but you do not want it erased; or

12.11.1.3 it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected, but we still need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or

12.11.1.4 you have exercised the right to object, and verification of overriding grounds is pending.

12.11.2 We can continue to use your personal information following a request for restriction, where:

12.11.2.1 we have your consent; or

12.11.2.2 to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or

12.11.2.3 to protect the rights of another natural or legal person. 

**12.12 Right to transfer your personal information**

12.12.1 You can ask us to provide your personal information to you in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format, or you can ask to have it transferred directly to another data controller, but in each case only where:

12.12.1.1 the processing is based on your consent or on the performance of a contract with you; and

12.12.1.2 the processing is carried out by automated means. 

**12.13 Right to object to the processing of your personal information**

12.13.1 You can object to any processing of your personal information which has our legitimate interests as its legal basis, if you believe your fundamental rights and freedoms outweigh our legitimate interests. 

12.13.2 If you raise an objection, we have an opportunity to demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate interests which override your rights and freedoms. 

**12.14 Right to object to how we use your personal information for direct marketing purposes**

12.14.1 You can request that we change the manner in which we contact you for marketing purposes.

12.14.2 You can request that we not transfer your personal information to unaffiliated third parties for the purposes of direct marketing or any other purposes.

**12.15 Right to obtain a copy of personal information safeguards used for transfers outside your jurisdiction**

12.15.1 You can ask to obtain a copy of, or reference to, the safeguards under which your personal information is transferred outside of the European Union. We may redact data transfer agreements to protect commercial terms.

**12.16 Right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority**

12.16.1 You have a right to lodge a complaint with your [local supervisory authority](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080) if you have concerns about how we are processing your personal information. 

12.16.2 We ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us first, although you have a right to contact your supervisory authority at any time.  

**13\. CONTACT US**

13.1.1 Questions, comments, requests or issues arising from this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to enquiry@icc-cricket.com.

13.1.2 If you have any questions, concerns or complaints regarding our compliance with this Privacy Policy and the data protection laws, or if you wish to exercise your rights, we encourage you to first contact us at [enquiry@icc-cricket.com]. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes and will make every reasonable effort to honour your wish to exercise your rights as quickly as possible and in any event, within the timescales provided by data protection laws.  

**13.2 To contact your data protection supervisory authority**

13.2.1 In some countries, you may have a right to lodge a complaint with your local [data protection supervisory authority](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080). We ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us before your local supervisory authority.
